Charles K. Panish papers, 1961-1987
American Numismatic Society
Charles K. Panish papers
1961 - 1987
Correspondence, notes, articles, booklets, article reprints, and background information about various regions and coins of the world, but mostly pertaining to Panish’s work researching, publishing, and collecting in the area of South Asian coins.
Panish, Charles K.
American Numismatic Society
5.3 cubic feet (6 boxes)
Biographical Note
Charles K. Panish (1907-1995) of Westport, Connecticut, was an expert on coins of South Asia. He volunteered his services to the American Numismatic Society (ANS) for over three decades, performing work for years as a virtual acting curator, attributing, rearranging, and relabeling over half of the South Asian coins, particularly in the collection of Indian States coins and those of the Himalayan states: Tibet, Nepal, Assam, and Ladakh. He became a member of ANS in 1951 and in 1960 joined the Committee on Oriental Coins. He was appointed chair of that committee in 1961, the same year he was elected an ANS fellow. He was also a major benefactor, donating 9,682 coins to ANS over the course of several decades, beginning in 1959.
Access
Collection open to all researchers.
Coins, South Asian--Collectors and collecting; Panish, Charles K; Indian Institute of Research in Numismatic Studies; Oriental Numismatic Society; Royal Numismatic Society (Great Britain); Society for Oriental Numismatics; Society for International Numismatics; Correspondence; Notes; Articles; Booklets; Reprints; Newsletters
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, notes, articles, booklets, article reprints, and background information about various regions and coins of the world, but mostly pertaining to Panish’s work researching, publishing, and collecting in the area of South Asian coins. Much of the correspondence has to do with his gathering of information on individual coins and other collectors and researchers seeking his expert advice on coins. There is about one cubic foot of mostly routine correspondence, newsletters, and other materials from various numismatic groups of which he was a member, such as the American Numismatic Society, Indian Institute of Research in Numismatic Studies, Oriental Numismatic Society, Royal Numismatic Society, The Society for Oriental Numismatics, and the Society for International Numismatics.
  nnan0087
- Box 1 of 6
    nnan0087/c_f195205144103a02c0b4b868e0306029
  - Afghan Autonomous Coinage (1964-1965)
  - Afghanistan: Gammon & Spengler (1966-1968)
  - Afghanistan: Paper Money (1965-1973)
  - Afghanistan: Notes (1963-1982)
  - Afghanistan: Basic Articles
  - Afghanistan: Bogdanov (Journal of the Asiatic Society of Bengal) (1928)
  - Afghanistan: Misc. Publications (1961-1965)
  - Arakan/Burmah (1985-1986)
  - Arakan: Etc. (1978-1979)
  - Arabic Mints (Browder) (1974, 1981)
  - Arakanese Coins (1982)
  - Arcot Rupees (1962-1982, bulk 1968-1971)
  - Armenia (1978-1979, 1986)
  - Assam Coinage (1971-1973, 1978)
  - Baroda Coins (1883, 1925, 1963-1981)
  - Bengal: History (circa 1930)
  - Bhartpur (circa 1976)
  - Bhutan (1971-1976)
  - Bhutan: Gobi Times (1969-1973)
  - British East India Co. (1960-1980)
  - British North Borneo Tokens (1986)
  - Burmah (1972-1984)
  - Byzantine/Campbell (1983, 1986-1989)
  - Cambodia (Battambang) (1975-1982)
  - Casts, Cleaning, Etc. (1962-1964, 1975)
  - Ceylon (1968, 1982)
  - China (1975, 1979-1980)
- Box 2 of 6
    nnan0087/c_bf50efe4e5afb23ca12c2422e07edd2f
  - Dating Oriental Coins (1974-1976, 1982-1983)
  - Denominations (circa 1968)
  - Egypt (1967-1971, 1977)
  - Ethiopia (1969-1980)
  - Frequency Curves (circa 1924)
  - Garhwal (United Provinces) (circa 1969)
  - Greek Counterstamps on Turkish Coins (1970)
  - Hyderabad: General Notes (1962-1976)
  - Hyderabad: History (Willmott) (circa 1884)
  - Hyderabad: Treaties (Briggs) (1861)
  - Story of Hyderbad Coinage, Etc. (1912-1982, bulk 1970-1972)
  - Indian States (Valentine) (1917)
  - Janjira/Kolaba/Nasik/Kanara
  - Indian Coinages (Bright) (1971-1977, bulk 1977)
  - Indian Scripts (Ojha) (1918, 1976)
  - South India (1883, 1977-1980)
  - Rajputana: Genl (1970-1972)
  - India Book: Correspondence I (1969-1970)
  - India Book: Correspondence II (1973-1975)
  - India Book: A-B (circa 1973)
  - India Book: C-F (circa 1976)
  - India Book: G-J (circa 1976)
  - India Book: K-Z (circa 1976)
  - Manipur (1972, 1974)
  - India Book: Misc. (circa 1976)
  - Heraldry
  - Kachar (1977, 1986)
  - Kushan: Gold (1960, 1976, 1983)
  - Kushan: Cribb
  - Kutch (1969, 1975, 1981)
  - Ladakh Coins (1969-1975, 1981-1982)
  - Articles: Native Coinages of the Malay Peninsula (1968-1974)
- Box 3 of 6
    nnan0087/c_269c691cfe63e282126c3411a2843bab
  - Malay States (1974-1981)
  - Maldive Islands (1963-1979)
  - Maratha Mints (1963-1985)
  - Moghal Mints (1953, 1975, 1981)
  - Morocco (1968-1984)
  - Mysore State (circa 1974)
  - Nepal (1969-1971)
  - Native States (Roster) (1910-1977)
  - Native States Integration (circa 1954)
  - Native Indian States (Misc.) (1963-1987)
  - Native Indian States II (1974-1977, 1981, 1986-1988)
  - Nepal (E Sikkam) (1958-1988)
  - Pakistan (1967-1968)
  - Persia (Iran) (1968-1975)
  - Russia (including Turkestan) (1962-1984)
  - Saudi Arabia (1967-1975)
  - Siamese Coins (1879, 1971-1985)
  - Tibet II (1971-1980, 1986-1987)
  - Tibet (1967-1986)
  - Tibet Slides (1969)
  - Tibetan Paper Money (1966-1979, 1986)
  - Travencore State (1894, 1965-1982)
  - Tripura State (1913-1914, 1965-1977)
- Box 4 of 6
    nnan0087/c_c9f044baf69d015dbf6f3e08edc2e37a
  - Tunis (1967-1975)
  - U.S. Bicentennial (1974-1979)
  - U.S. Currency (circa 1959)
  - India: Correspondence and Photographs (1960-1980)
  - India: Correspondence II (1971)
  - India: Correspondence III (1972)
  - World Coinage (1962-1975)
  - Yeman (1918)
- Box 5 of 6
    nnan0087/c_77a4c6e43b84dfbdd8505fab7f022b1d
  - American Numismatic Association Certification Service (1973, 1981-1988)
  - ANS: Correspondence, Newsletters I (1976-1983)
  - ANS: Correspondence, Newsletters II (1983-1986)
  - ANS: Correspondence, Newsletters III (1986-1990)
  - Bombay Numismatic Society (1977-1981)
  - Indian Institute of Research in Numismatic Studies (1980-1988)
  - India-Asiatic Numismatic Society (1971-1973)
  - India-Asiatic Numismatic Society II (1972-1974)
  - International Bank Note Society (1974-1979)
  - International Numismatic Society (INS) (1977-1988)
  - Malaysia Numismatic Society (1973-1981)
  - Maryland Paper Money Club (1968-1974)
  - Numismatics International (1969-1984)
  - Numismatics International: Attribution Committee (1984-1990)
  - Numismatics Society of India (1977-1988)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society: Info Sheets I (1973-1979)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society: Info Sheets II (1977-1990)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society I (1970-1974)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society II (1974-1976)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society III (1976-1987)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society: Newsletter I (1970-1976)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society: Newsletter II (1974-1985)
  - Oriental Numismatic Society: Newsletter III (1985-1990)
  - Primitive Money Club (1975)
  - Royal Numismatic Society (1969, 1973-1988)
  - The Society for International Numismatics (S.I.N.) (1967-1978)
  - The Society for Oriental Numismatics (S.O.N.) (1975-1976)
- Box 6 of 6
    nnan0087/c_557451b946f4030667e5d01561986f37
  - Misc. Publications: National Geographic (August, 1946, May, 1949, July 1955, October 1965, October, 1966), American Numismatic Association, Numismatic Association of Bombay (June, 1979 and June, 1980)
  - Manuscript: The Copper Coins of India (1921)
  - Correspondence and Manuscript: Codrington-Princep rubbing book (circa 1974)
  - Rubbings of Coins of India
  - Dating Systems on Coins Since 1000 A.D. (1974, 1983)
  - Turkey (Ottoman): Correspondence and Photographs (1950-1975)
  - Chinese Turkestan (1969-1980)
  - Seaby’s Indian Coins (1905, 1950-1960)
  - U.S. Army: Certificates, Correspondence and Photographs (1946-1967)
  - Manuscript: The Coins of North Cambodia
  - Manuscript: The Maharshahi Rupee of Bagalkot
  - Coins of Tibet: Lecture Notes, Correspondence, Rubbings and Photographs (1969)
  - Norwalk, Connecticut Coin Club (1967-1971)
  - Misc. U.S. Army Publications: Retired Army Bulletin, Commander’s Digest, The Officer (1968-1978)
  - Citizen’s Action Committee of Norwalk, Inc. (1966-1973)
  - Social Security Administration: Department of Health, Education and Welfare (1979) Organization of International Numismatists: Manual of by-laws, policies and procedures (1970)
  - Civilian Personnel Records (1941-1965)
  - Kelly: Universal Cambist (1835)
  - Misc. Coinage Articles
  - Coins of the Moslem States of the Deccan (1979)
  - Numismatic International Attribution Committee Service Requests (1981-1986)
  - Sikh Coins (1967, 1972, 1978-1981)
  - Correspondence I (1983-1984)
  - Correspondence II (1984-1985)
  - Correspondence III (1985-1987)
  - Correspondence IV (1987-1989)
  - Correspondence V(1989-1990)